Guide to the Susan G. Bell Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Susan G. Bell papers
1978-1982
SC0555
Bell, Susan G.
1 Linear feet
This collection contains curriculum materials arranged in three series. The first series is from the Stanford Institute of Women's History, 1978, a workshop attended by high school teachers from across the country. Included are outlines, suggested readings, copies of readings, topics for discussion, and explanatory text. The second series is from a curriculum project on women in western civilization undertaken by the Organization of American Historians with support from the Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education. Included are syllabi, reading lists, introductory notes, and topics for discussion. The third series consists of readings from the Faculty Seminar in Feminist Studies at Stanford for 1981 and 1982.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Gift of Susan G. Bell, 1997.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Susan Groag Bell is a historian and Affiliated Scholar at the Stanford Institute for Research on Women and Gender. She has published numerous books and articles on women's history.
Description of the Collection
This collection contains curriculum materials arranged in three series. The first series is from the Stanford Institute of Women's History, 1978, a workshop attended by high school teachers from across the country. Included are outlines, suggested readings, copies of readings, topics for discussion, and explanatory text. The second series is from a curriculum project on women in western civilization undertaken by the Organization of American Historians with support from the Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education. Included are syllabi, reading lists, introductory notes, and topics for discussion. The third series consists of readings from the Faculty Seminar in Feminist Studies at Stanford for 1981 and 1982.
Access Terms
Bell, Susan G.; Organization of American Historians.; Stanford Institute of Women's History.; Women --History --Study and teaching (Higher) --United States.; Women --History --Study and teaching (Secondary) --United States
Collection Contents
- Stanford Institute of Women's History: High School, Series 1
  - Outline, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chicana and Chicano Family, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Demography, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Women and Work Outside the Home, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Housewife and Her Work, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Women and Work: Oral History, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sex and Education in American History, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - In Her Own Words, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- OAH. FIPSE. Women in Western Civilization Curriculum Readings, Series 2
  - Western Civilization I, Unit 1 (up to 1600), part A, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Western Civilization I, Unit 1 (up to 1600), part B, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Western Civilization I, Unit 2 (1600-1789), Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Western Civilization II, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Faculty Seminar in Feminist Studies, Series 3
  - Readings I, Introduction/Letters, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Readings I, Aeschylus-Catullus, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Readings I, Dante-Foley, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Readings I, Homer-Power, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Readings I, Ruether-Virgil, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Readings II, Introduction/Letters, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Readings II, Brooks-Freud, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Readings II, Haining-Lydon, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Readings II, Marx-"Why Are Women Witches Oftener than Men?", 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)